<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.kovzol.bibref</id>

  <name>bibref</name>
  <summary>Discover references in the Bible</summary>

  <url type="homepage">https://kovzol.github.io/bibref</url>

  <developer id="io.github.kovzol">
    <name>Zoltán Kovács</name>
  </developer>

  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>FSFAP</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      <em>bibref</em> is a tool that helps discovering internal references in the Bible. It aims at finding citations of the Septuagint in the Greek New Testament in a mechanical way.
      </p>
      <p>
        The Bible, a book that has been translated into many languages, is maybe the most important book has ever existed. Believers have evidence that it is God&apos;s word, written by various people being inspired by God himself.
      </p>
      <p>
        The Bible has many internal references. Many of them connect the two parts of the Bible: the Old Testament and the New Testament. The books of the Old Testament are usually written in Hebrew, while the books of the New Testament are Greek. A natural question can arise: How can Hebrew texts be cited in the Greek text?
      </p>
      <p>
        There are several research projects on this, and today it seems to be clear that many authors of the New Testament cited a Greek translation of the Hebrew text, namely the Septuagint, that was widely popular in the first centuries, and still popular in some Christian churches. Many Bible translations, however, mostly use only the Hebrew text as a basis of the Old Testament, because the importance of the Septuagint is not yet widely identified.
      </p>
      <p>
        This software project attempts to support finding citations of the Septuagint in the New Testament automatically. The work is based on The SWORD Project.
      </p>
      <p>
        The <em>bibref</em> package offers several tools that help in comparing the verses of the Septuagint with the verses of the Greek New Testament. The tools consider the texts of full books of the Bible as one unit instead of considering just separated verses. The texts are provided by the SWORD project from the modules LXX and SBLGNT. In the newest versions the module StatResGNT is also supported.
      </p>
    </description>

    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.kovzol.bibref.desktop</launchable>
    <screenshots>
      <screenshot type="default">
        <image>https://github.com/kovzol/bibref/blob/master/bibref-qt.png?raw=true</image>
        <caption>Some simple queries made with bibref</caption>
      </screenshot>
    </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="2024Sep26" date="2024-09-26">
    <url type="details">https://github.com/kovzol/bibref/commits/065710e4e8c03d35df4764713db3034616e867cd/</url>
      <description>
        <p>Release description</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Fix output formatting for the search command</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2024Mar30" date="2024-03-30">
    <url type="details">https://github.com/kovzol/bibref/commits/a3cc208db13bee3825a1fcf347bb30a10d97fc99/</url>
      <description>
        <p>Release description</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Syntax hints shown as tooltips</li>
            <li>Help menu points to the web based terminal version</li>
            <li>Some icons added to Help menu options</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2024Mar14" date="2024-03-14">
    <url type="details">https://github.com/kovzol/bibref/commits/83aacb891e45fdddec3e7266396841808fb279d3/</url>
      <description>
        <p>Release description</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Remove markdown code from HTML documentation</li>
            <li>Color support</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2024Mar06" date="2024-03-06">
    <url type="details">https://github.com/kovzol/bibref/commits/787948273e9dbc720c2ac0ec967658b579169a15/</url>
      <description>
        <p>Release description</p>
          <ul>
            <li>First flathub version</li>
            <li>Qt interface</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  </component>
